

Contacts

919691346

✓ luis.simoes.T0126214@edu.atec.pt

luismcs.github.io / github.com/Luismcs

https://www.linkedin.com/in/luissimoes-developer/

Porto, Portugal

Digital Skills

Java 21

Spring Framework

PHP

Laravel

C#

SQL,

GIT & Github

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Soft Skills

Organized

Teamwork

Taking Notes

Languages

Portuguese (native)

English (advanced)

Luís Simões

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am an enthusiast for technology, with a strong passion for learning and a commitment to continuous improvement mostly in Backend Development. Adaptable, disciplined, and growth-oriented, I thrive in challenging software development environments, contributing effectively to team success while expanding my expertise.

Experience

09/2024 - 11/2024

Junior Java Developer at HumanIT (Internship)

- Completed a Java Academy focused on backend development with Java 21 and Spring Framework, enhancing technical and practical skills.
- Designed and implemented multiple backend projects, including APIs and microservices, applying best practices in software development.
- Collaborated closely with a Senior Developer, receiving mentorship on code quality, debugging, and clean architecture.
- Completed courses on project management methodologies, such as Scrum, and participated in technical English training sessions, enhancing the ability to communicate in professional environments.

12/2020 - 06/2021

IT Team member at Escola Secundária da Boa Nova (Internship)

- Maintained IT school equipment.
- Developed a website for the course in Wix.

Projects

05/2024 - 07/2024

Qualitask

- Technologies: Laravel, Blade, MySQL, Javascript, AWS
- Developed a solution for attendance tracking and management of schedules, shifts, absences, and vacations.
- Implemented data import/export functionalities and metrics generation in dashboards.

11/2024- Still going

Salary Management Portal

- Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Docker
- Developed a microservices platform for managing collaborators, salaries, and report export using RabbitMQ.
- Features include JWT authentication, dashboards, and automated email report delivery.

Education

06/2023 - 11/2024

Technical Course in Computer Management and Programming

Systems (Level 5)- ATEC Academia de Formação

- Programming Languages: C#,C++.
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel.
- Database: SQL, SQL Server.
- Operative Systems: Windows 2019 Server, Linux Debian.
- Networking: Cisco Packet Tracer.
- Other: Git, GitHub, APIs.
- Website: www.atec.pt

09/2018 - 06/2021

Technical Course in Computer Management and Programming

Systems (Level 4)- Escola Secundária da Boa Nova

- Programming Languages: C++, Java.
- Web Development: HTML.
- Database: MySQL.